Oh, they have that store in Tokyo, too?
Davvero? Anche a Tokyo c'era quel negozio?
There was always a line. You'd have to wait a whole hour.
C'era sempre la fila. Potevi aspettare anche un'ora intera.
Ya made it, Komichi.
Komichi, appena in tempo.
M-Morning...
B-Buongiorno...
Unusual for you to just barely get here in time.
È strano vederti arrivare al pelo.
They said Tamura-sensei's running a little late.
Pare che la professoressa Tamura sia un po' in ritardo.
Thank goodness.
Meno male!
Akebi-san, Akebi-san!
Akebi, Akebi!
That's me!
Eh? Sì?
Is it true you're dancing at the after-party?
Davvero ballerai al dopo-festival?
Roubai Academy Athletic Festival After-Party Program • Opening Speech • After-Party Planning Committee Vice President (Class 3-4 Takayama Haru) • Stage Program • 1. Quiz Competition: "How Many Do You Know?! Secrets of Roubai Academy" (After-Party Planning Committee) 2. Acoustic Guitar and Singing (Class 2-3 Soumi Ruri) Short Film "As We Accelerate" (Film Research Club) 4. Band Performance (Radical☆Pop) 5. Dance (Drama Club: Akebi Komichi)
Festival Sportivo Accademia Roubai Dopo-Festival Programma • Discorso di Apertura • Vice Presidente del Comitato Organizzativo del Dopo-Festival (Haru Takayama Classe 3-4) • Programma Palco • 1. Gara a Quiz: "Quanti ne sai?! I Segreti dell'Accademia Roubai" (Comitato Organizzativo del Dopo-Festival) 2. Canto e Chitarra Acustica (Ruri Soumi Classe 2-3) Cortometraggio "Mentre acceleriamo" (Club di Ricerca Cinematografica) 4. Gruppo Musicale (Radical☆Pop) 5. Danza (Club di Teatro: Komichi Akebi)
Oh... Yeah, for the drama club.
Oh... Sì, per il club di teatro.
I thought about joining the program, but didn't...
Avevo pensato anch'io di partecipare, ma...
But I'll come watch for sure!
Però ci sarò senz'altro a vederti!
I can't wait to see you!
Non vedo davvero l'ora!
I'll be there, too!
Ci sarò anch'io!
Thanks!
Grazie!
That's pretty cool, Komichi.
È incredibile, Komichi.
What're ya gonna dance to? What song?
Su cosa ballerai? Quale canzone?
I've actually already started practicing.
A dire il vero ho già iniziato ad allenarmi.
2. Acoustic Guitar and Singing (Class 2-3 Soumi Ruri) Short Film "As We Accelerate" (Film Research Club) 4. Band Performance (Radical☆Pop) 5. Dance (Drama Club: Akebi Komichi) 6. Catch the Rhythm! Medley of Popular Songs (Brass Band Club) Closing Speech After-Party Planning Committee President (Class 3-2 Hanasato Yuka) Time: After the Athletic Festival's Closing Ceremony Place: Roubai Auditorium
2. Canto e Chitarra Acustica (Ruri Soumi Classe 2-3) Cortometraggio "Mentre acceleriamo" (Club di Ricerca Cinematografica) 4. Gruppo Musicale (Radical☆Pop) 5. Danza (Club di Teatro: Komichi Akebi) 6. Tieni il Ritmo! Medley di Canzoni Popolari (Club degli Ottoni) Discorso di Chiusura Presidente del Club Organizzativo del Dopo-Festival (Yuka Hanasato Classe 3-2) Quando: dopo la Cerimonia di Chiusura del Festival Sportivo Dove: Auditorium Roubai
I was practicing this morning before I came here.
Lo stavo facendo stamattina prima di venire qui.
Oh, so that's why you came in just under the wire.
Oh, ecco perché sei arrivata al pelo.
Well... there it is.
Oh... eccolo.
I shouldn't butt in.
Non dovrei ficcare il naso.
Hey, Kizaki-san...
Senti, Kizaki...
You can play piano, too, right?
Tu sai suonare anche il piano, vero?
Huh?
Eh?
I heard you playing the one in the music room when I was cleaning before.
Ti ho sentito suonare quello nell'aula di musica quando facevo le pulizie.
Plus, there's a piano in your room, right?
E poi c'è un piano nella tua stanza, no?
I bet if you played the piano for Akebi-chan to dance to at the after-party,
Scommetto che se suonassi il piano per Akebi al dopo-festival,
everyone would love it!
ne sarebbero tutte entusiaste!
Huh?
Eh?
You know, I have a CD of the song by Miki-chan that Akebi-chan is dancing to.
Sai, ho il CD della canzone di Miki su cui ballerà Akebi.
Huh?
Eh?
It's a really nice song with a piano accompaniment!
È davvero un bel brano con accompagnamento al piano!
What?!
Eeeh?!
Yeah, so...
Quindi pensavo...
H-Hey, I'm just wishing out loud! Don't be mad, okay?
E-Ehi, stavo solo pensando ad alta voce. Non arrabbiarti, ok?
Forget I said anything!
Fa' finta che non abbia detto niente!
Oh, by the way, when I saw Ai in the entryway today—
Oh, a proposito, quando ho visto Ai nell'atrio oggi—
I'm not mad!
Non sono arrabbiata!
I'm just a little surprised, that's all.
Solo un po' sorpresa, tutto qui.
Really?
Davvero?
What a relief!
Che sollievo!
Oh, hey, I made snacks.
Oh, ho fatto dei biscotti.
Want some?
Ne vuoi?
Just one.
Solo uno.
It's very good.
È buono.
I can't say whether everyone would love it,
Non so se ne saranno tutte entusiaste,
but I can play the piano.
ma posso farlo...
A little.
Un pochino.
Episode Eleven Sharing This Time... With Everyone...
Episodio Undici Condividere questo momento... con tutte quante...
Oops.
Ops.
Receive!
Ricezione!
I got it!
Ci penso io!
Ow!
Ahia!
Ouch...
Che male...
A-Are you okay?
S-State bene?
You two really are close, huh?
Siete proprio in sintonia, eh?
But that doesn't matter if you can't keep the ball in the air.
Ma non serve a niente se non mantenete la palla in aria.
This isn't working at all!
Così non funziona per niente!
These team events are so important, and yet...
E dire che gli eventi di gruppo sono così importanti...
They're worth a lot of points, and the final round is the last event of the festival.
Valgono un sacco di punti e l'ultimo turno è l'evento finale del festival.
There'll be a lot of people there.
Ci sarà pure una gran folla.
What should we do?
Che facciamo?
It'd be great if we could get all six of us together for a training camp on a day off.
Sarebbe bello se potessimo andare in ritiro tutte e sei assieme, quando non siamo a scuola.
A training camp with all of us?
In ritiro?
I mean, it's a team event.
Sì, è un evento di gruppo.
We need all six of us.
Dobbiamo farcela tutte e sei assieme.
I was...
Io invece...
only thinking about how I could practice myself.
mi stavo concentrando solo su me stessa.
We don't have a place where we can all practice, though.
Comunque non abbiamo un posto dove andare.
A place...
Un posto...
If only there was a gym we could use on a day off.
Se solo avessimo una palestra dove allenarci quando non veniamo a scuola.
Oh!
Oh!
Hello, Komori residence.
Pronto, casa Komori.
Good evening, Mako-sensei. This is Akebi Komichi.
Buonasera, maestra Mako. Sono Komichi Akebi.
Oh, Komichi-chan! It's been so long!
Oh, Komichi! Quanto tempo!
It's good to talk to you again.
Sì, parecchio!
Are you busy at the moment?
La disturbo adesso?
What's this about? There's no need to be so polite.
Che succede? Non c'è bisogno di essere così formali.
So, how is Roubai Academy?
Allora, come va all'Accademia Roubai?
It's so much fun!
Mi diverto tantissimo!
We're having our athletic festival soon.
Ah, presto ci sarà il festival sportivo.
Oh, that does sound like fun.
Oh, ma che bello!
Well, actually... the thing is...
Ecco, a dire il vero...
You want to bring your classmates to Futaba Elementary's gym to practice?
Vuoi portare le tue compagne di classe ad allenarsi nella palestra della scuola elementare Futaba?
Yes, of course you can use the gym.
Ma certo, va benissimo!
Thank—
Grazie—
I'm so happy.
Sono così felice.
Huh?
Eh?
You were always talking about how you wanted friends.
Komichi... dicevi sempre di volere delle amiche.
For six years, I only knew you as the only little girl in her class.
Per sei anni sei stata l'unica bambina della tua classe.
I always told you that I was sure you'd make lots of friends someday,
Ti ho sempre detto che ero sicura avresti avuto un sacco di amiche un giorno,
but there was nothing more I could do,
ma non potevo fare altro per te
and that just broke my heart.
e ci stavo male, molto male.
But I'm so glad.
Ma ora sono così sollevata.
You really did make friends.
Sei riuscita a farti delle amiche.
That alone...
Già questo...
makes me so happy.
mi rende felicissima.
Okay...
Capisco...
Thank you.
La ringrazio.
How'd it go?
Com'è andata?
Mako-sensei said...
La maestra Mako...
we can use the gym.
ha detto che possiamo usare la palestra.
W a s h i o H i t o m i
H i t o m i W a s h i o
N a w s h i r o Y a s u k o
Y a s u k o N a w s h i r o
Oh...
Capisco...
Well, you can't help it if your club's meeting.
Se c'è di mezzo il club, non si può evitare.
Yeah. I'm sorry.
Già, mi spiace.
This sucks.
Che peccato.
I don't see why our club has to meet on a Sunday.
Non capisco perché il club debba riunirsi pure la domenica.
Right, Hitomi-chan?
Tu sì, Hitomi?
Roubai's volleyball club is the most accomplished of all the clubs.
Il club di pallavolo è quello con più risultati.
What're you writing?
Che stai scrivendo?
An application.
Una richiesta.
Anyway, Akebi-chan and the other girls sure are motivated, huh?
Comunque, Akebi e le altre sono davvero molto motivate, non credi?
It's just a dumb athletic festival.
È solo uno stupido festival sportivo.
Aw, don't call it dumb.
Non dire che è stupido.
I'm gonna be in the cheer squad along with Akebi-chan, you know...
Io farò il tifo assieme ad Akebi, sai...
Huh?
Eh?
So those two can't make it...
Loro due non possono, eh?
Okay!
E va bene!
K i z a k i E r i k a
E r i k a K i z a k i
Oh...
Oh...
Uh-huh.
Uh-huh.
Komichi's elementary school on Sunday?
La scuola elementare di Komichi di domenica?
Sounds like fun.
Sembra divertente.
Sure, that's fine.
Sì, va bene.
Thanks!
Grazie!
What? Mikan from your parents?
Eh? I tuoi genitori ci offrono dei mandarini?
That's awesome!
Che bello!
Okay, then, see you tomorrow!
Ok, allora a domani!
Wait, I don't have time to sit here celebrating!
Ehi, non c'è tempo per gongolare!
I'm gonna get better at volleyball!
Devo migliorare, costi quel che costi!
I wanna go, too.
Voglio venire anch'io...
I'm going to practice volleyball.
Io vado ad allenarmi a pallavolo.
I'm not just going to play around.
Non vado a divertirmi.
I'll practice, too!
Voglio esercitarmi anch'io!
It's boring playing in the gym by myself all the time.
Mi annoio a giocare sempre da sola in palestra.
I said "playing"...
Ho detto "giocare"...
She's so squishy!
Che morbidosa!
I didn't know you were a big sister, Komichi.
Komichi, non sapevo avessi una sorellina.
So smooth...
Com'è liscia...
Yep.
Già.
Hey, guys!
Ragazze!
So squishy...
Morbidosa...
Usagihara-san!
Usagihara!
Morning!
Ciao!
Morning.
Ciao.
Nawashiro-san and Washio-san had to go to their club.
Nawashiro e Washio avevano un raduno del club,
But they'll come in the afternoon.
ma verranno nel pomeriggio.
Whew, I'm glad we got here in time!
Oh, siamo arrivate in tempo!
Huh? Wait, how?
Eh? Cosa?
You're big!
Sei grande!
What is this?
E questa chi è?
What is this little thing?
Chi è questa piccoletta?
Oh, crap!
Oh, accidenti!
The bus'll be here any moment!
Il bus sta per arrivare!
Okay, so what the heck happened?
Allora, cos'è successo?
Well, right after you went back to your room...
Beh, appena te ne sei andata...
Request for Permission to Leave the Grounds
Permesso di Uscita
To the Roubai Academy Head of Student Affairs
Al responsabile degli affari studenteschi dell'Accademia Roubai
Names:    Class 1-3, Washio Hitomi
Nomi:    Hitomi Washio Classe 1-3
Class 1-3 Nawashiro Yasuko
Yasuko Nawashiro Classe 1-3
[Reasons for Request]
[Motivo della Richiesta]
To practice for the athletic festival volleyball event
Allenamento per il torneo di pallavolo del festival sportivo
You really went to all that trouble?
Eh? Hai fatto tutta quella trafila?
You're totally just ditchin'.
State solo saltando le attività del club.
She told them it was for volleyball practice, same as our club.
Ha scritto che era per allenarsi a pallavolo, come per il nostro club.
I didn't lie, and the captain approved.
Non ho mentito e il capitano ha dato l'approvazione.
We're not asking too much, are we?
Non stiamo chiedendo troppo, vero?
Why are you making that face?
Perché fai quella faccia?
You should be happy that all six of us are together to practice.
Dovresti essere contenta che ci siamo tutte e sei.
You want to win, don't you?
Vuoi vincere, no?
Yeah.
Sì.
And you said we're going to win, right?
E avete detto che avremmo vinto, no?
Did I say that?
Davvero l'ho detto?
What?! Riri-san?!
Eh?! Riri?!
Yeah, I did. You're so gullible, Komichi.
Sì, l'ho detto. Sei una credulona, Komichi.
Hey! That was mean!
Ehi! Non trattarmi così!
That was funny!
È stato divertente!
It looks like a pretty old building.
È un edificio piuttosto vecchio.
Like something you'd see in a movie.
Del tipo che si vede nei film.
I'll go get the key from the teacher.
Vado a farmi dare la chiave dalla maestra.
Kao, you take the lead.
Kao, accompagnale tu intanto.
It's this way!
Per di qua!
Mako-sensei.
Maestra Mako.
Komichi-chan!
Komichi!
Here you go.
Eccola, prego.
Thanks.
La ringrazio.
The net and balls are in the equipment room.
La rete e i palloni sono nello stanzino degli attrezzi.
Think you can find them?
Pensi di farcela?
We've got girls from the volleyball club. We'll be fine!
Ci sono anche delle ragazze del club di pallavolo. Andrà tutto bene!
I see. How many friends did you bring?
Capisco. Quante amiche hai portato?
Five. And Kao, too.
Cinque... e c'è pure Kao.
Well, good luck.
Fate del vostro meglio!
I'll be by to peek in on you all later.
Verrò a sbirciare un pochino più tardi.
Okay!
Ok!
All right, let's get started.
Bene, cominciamo!
Nice one!
Nice!
One more!
Ancora!
Komichi's gotten a lot better.
Komichi è migliorata un sacco!
I know. She's better than me now.
Vero. È più brava di me.
Hey, who's in the volleyball club?
Ehi, club di pallavolo!
One more, please!
Ancora una, per favore!
Are you enjoying it that much?
Ti stai divertendo così tanto?
Yeah.
Sì.
I guess... I'm just so happy.
Che dire... sono felice.
It used to be just me and Kao in this gym,
In questa palestra c'eravamo sempre soltanto io e Kao,
but now so many of my classmates are here with me,
ma ora sono qui con le mie compagne di classe
and we're all able to practice together.
e possiamo allenarci assieme.
It won't help if you're only good when you're here.
Non serve a niente se sei brava solo qui.
The main event's still ahead.
C'è ancora tempo per l'evento.
Yeah, but I'm starting to enjoy this now, too.
Però... anch'io inizio a trovarlo divertente.
Yeah! I haven't been letting the ball drop as much!
Già! Io non ho perso poi tante palle!
Last run before our break! Let's go!
L'ultima prima della pausa! Andiamo!
Yeah!
Sì!
To a Shining Future
Per un Futuro Radioso
Akebi-chan! Attack!
Akebi! Schiaccia!
Break time!
Pausa!
I'm burnin' up!
Che...
M-Minakami-san!
M-Minakami!
This isn't the place to take off your clothes!
Non è questo il luogo in cui spogliarsi!
C'mon, what's the problem?
Eddai, che problema c'è?
Wait! Stop!
Ferma! Ferma!
You're all sweaty, too. C'mon, show me whatcha got.
Anche tu sei sudata. Fa' vedere cos'hai!
I'll change in the locker room!
Vado a cambiarmi nello spogliatoio!
Kao-chan, we've got an undresser on our hands!
Kao, abbiamo tra le mani una spogliatrice!
Pin her down!
Bloccala a terra!
Roger!
Roger!
Hey!
Ehi!
Take her shorts off, too!
Le tolgo pure i pantaloncini!
Huh?!
Eh?!
Now, now, hold still!
Su, su, sta' ferma!
Wait, seriously, don't!
Ehi, ferme, non fatelo!
Hold still!
Sta' ferma!
They saved me...
Sono salva...
No!
Nooo!
Wha...
Oh, no...
You too, Akebi-san?!
Anche tu, Akebi?!
Ready to get started now?
Che ne dite di ricominciare?
All right...
Pronta...
Akebi-chan...
Akebi...
Where's the restroom?
Dov'è il bagno?
The gym restroom is out of order.
Quello della palestra è guasto.
I'll go, too. You can follow me.
Devo andarci anch'io. Vieni con me.
This school really is old, huh?
È una scuola proprio vecchia.
Yeah. It's gonna be closed down once Kao graduates.
Sì. Verrà chiusa quando Kao avrà finito l'ultimo anno.
Huh?
Eh?
That's why I'm so glad...
Per questo sono felice.
that my memories of my elementary school include you guys now.
Tra i ricordi delle mie elementari adesso ci siete anche voi.
I was scared to use the restroom right up until third grade.
Fino alla terza ho avuto paura di usare il bagno.
I always asked the teacher to wait by the door for me.
Chiedevo sempre alla maestra di aspettare dietro la porta.
So now I wish I could tell my younger self
Così ora vorrei poter dire alla me più piccola
that I'm washing my hands with a friend now.
che mi sto lavando le mani con un'amica.
Akebi-chan...
Akebi...
Well, maybe I'll go peek in on them now.
Bene, forse è il momento di dare una sbirciatina.
Remember to stretch.
Mi raccomando lo stretching.
What should we do about the rotation?
Come facciamo con le rotazioni?
Let's use rock-paper-scissors to pick teams for now.
Per ora facciamo a sasso-carta-forbici.
Oh, Mako-sensei!
Oh, maestra Mako!
Komichi-chan...
Komichi...
You have so many...
Sono così tante...
Come on, Kamimoku-san! You can't sleep here!
Ehi, Kamimoku! Non puoi dormire qui!
Oh! They're here!
Oh! Sono arrivate!
When I heard Nawashiro-san and Washio-san wouldn't be able to make it,
Quando ho saputo che Nawashiro e Washio non sarebbero venute,
I put out a call to everyone in class.
ho chiamato tutto il resto della classe.
Onee-chan, lots of people came!
Komichi, sono tantissime!
Usagihara-san!
Usagihara!
Whoa...
Oh...
C'mon, it's too hot.
Dai che fa caldo!
I really... really get to practice with everyone.
Posso allenarmi con tutte... proprio con tutte quante!
Sorry, though. Kizaki-san was the only one
Mi spiace. Kizaki ha detto che non poteva venire
who couldn't come because she had to practice something else.
perché doveva esercitarsi per qualcos'altro.
But it's still for the athletic festival, so go easy on her.
Ma sempre per il festival sportivo. Non avercela con lei.
I messed up again.
Ho sbagliato di nuovo.
Fukumoto Miki Music Note Interior
Miki Fukumoto Note Musicali Interiori
The tempo's so quick, it's hard to play.
Il tempo è veloce. È difficile.
I see.
Capisco...
Well, there are lots of things you need to be alone to practice.
Ci sono anche un sacco di cose in cui ci si allena da soli.
Fukumoto Miki Music Note Interior
Fukumoto Miki Note Musicali Interiori
I know Komichi-san will...
Sono certa che Komichi...
Sharing this time...
Voglio condividere questo momento...
with everyone...
con tutte quante...
Here I go!
Vado!
Onee-chan, today was fun, wasn't it?
Komichi... è stato divertente, vero?
It sure was.
Sì!
Think you'll be able to win at the athletic festival?
Pensi di poter vincere al festival sportivo?
Yeah.
Sì...
As long as we're all together.
Se restiamo così unite...
Roubai Academy Athletic Festival
Festival Sportivo Accademia Roubai
We'll win for sure!
vinceremo di sicuro!